Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Man with mustache sitting on chair, leaning on elbow on a table. 10 x 6.2 cm, Circa 1865; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Men; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Andon Hisaryan standing with a book in his hand, leaning on an upholstered chair. Name written on back in pencil. 10.6 x 6.5 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Men; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Books; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Ottoman Writing; French Writing
- Woman in glasses, holding a white cloth, sitting next to a table with books. Identical to ref79. 11 x 6.7 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Books; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Studio Photography; French Writing
- Emir Abdelkader (Abd al-Qādir ibn Muḥy al-dīn), (6 September 1808 – 26 May 1883). The inscription on the reverse incorrectly describes this photograph as Seyyid Abdülkadir. 10 x 6.3 cm, Circa 1860s; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Books; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Furnishings; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Ottoman Writing; Studio Photography; Political Leadership; Medals/Insignia; Regional/National Dress
- Sura-yi Devlet azasi (member of the state council) Muhsin Bey. 10.6 x 6.4 cm, 10 April 1888; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Men; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Cairo, Egypt; Facial Hair; Turkish Writing; Ottoman Writing; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Dr. Ali Haydar Bey (1880-1923). 10.4 x 6.1 cm, 1865; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Turkish Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Fur Garments; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Doctors; Men; Constantinople; Ottoman Writing
- William Gottlieb Schauffler (August 22, 1798 – January 27, 1883), German missionary, and his wife Mary R. Schauffler (née Reynolds). Names written on front. 10.4 x 6.3 cm, Circa 1868; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Men; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Women; Group Portraits; French Writing
- Vezir Mehmed Memduh Pasa (1839-1925), statesman, writer, poet. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Pens/Inkwells; Furnishings; Books; Poetry; Studio Photography; Turkish Writing; Ottoman Writing; Constantinople; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Men; Facial Hair
- Therese Honegger as a young girl. Subject also in ref51 and ref8. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Studio Photography; Children; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Religious Crosses; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Portrait of an Ottoman Prince. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Children; Hats; Boys; Fez/Tarboush; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Furnishings; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Ottoman Writing; French Writing
- Girl standing on chair, leaning on pillow. 10.4 x 6.3 cm, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Children; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Constantinople; Girls; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Woman standing in a light-colored dress with dark lace trim. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Constantinople; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; French Writing
- Man with mustache wearing a fez and patterned tie. 14.1 x 10.6 cm, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Skopje, Macedonia; Men; Ottoman Writing; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Hats; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- Portrait of Miss Laura Farnham (1844-1919), principal of a school in Adapazari, Turkey. 14.3 x 9.7 cm, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Embroidery; Women; Gelatin Silver Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; English Writing; Teachers; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints
- Man in three-piece suit with goatee beard. 10.3 x 6.1 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Men; Facial Hair; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Woman in lace trimmed dress, holding a hand fan, sitting on chair. 10.5 x 6.4 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Constantinople; Furnishings; Hand Fans; Albumen Prints; Ottoman Writing
- Yegane Hanim. 10.1 x 6.2 cm, 1860 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Jewelry; Books; Furnishings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Women; Ottoman Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople
- Man with side whiskers style beard in dark coat. 10.9 x 6.6 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Men; Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Woman in glasses, holding a white cloth, sitting next to a table with books. Identical to ref63. 11 x 6.7 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Books; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Ottoman Writing; French Writing
- Man with a mustache wearing a fez, holding a book. 16.9 x 11.3 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Jewelry; Books; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Men; Facial Hair
- Standing man in uniform, holding gloves and a walking stick. Possibly Dr. Kirimli Aziz Bey (1840-1878). 16.6 x 10.7 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Albumen Prints; Uniforms; Doctors; Gloves; Canes/Walking Sticks; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Painted Backdrops; Turkish Writing; Furnishings; Ottoman Writing; Men; Photographic Prints
- Soldier with a sword and gloves. 16.5 x 10.7 cm, 1884; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Hats; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Gloves; Fez/Tarboush; Embroidery; Books; Medals/Insignia; Furnishings; Men; Swords/Knives; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Weapons; French Writing
- Man with fez and mustache with a medal pinned to his chest. 16.4 x 10.9 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Medals/Insignia; French Writing
- Man with large mustache in a dark coat. 16.6 x 10.6 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Bow Ties; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Facial Hair; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Portrait of Caroline Livadari. 10.1 x 6.2 cm, 1875 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Religious Crosses; Women; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Jewelry; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man with mustache, wearing fez, standing with hand on chair. Numbers written on front. 10.5 x 6.2 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Furnishings; Men; French Writing
- Suleymaniye Mosque. 18.8 x 17.1 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Suleymaniye Mosque; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Bridges
- Uchisar and Uchisar Castle, Cappadocia. 18.1 x 23.9 cm, Circa 1950 (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey; Uchisar, Cappadocia; Architecture; Houses; Landscapes; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
- Karkamis Iron Bridge (1917) passing over the Euphrates river in Karkamis, Turkey and a camel. 17.9 x 24.4 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Camels; Bridges; Gelatin Silver Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Animals; Landscapes; German Writing; Euphrates River
- Rumelihisari Castle. 23.8 x 18 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Military/Soldiers; Snow; Istanbul, Turkey; Rumelihisari, Istanbul, Turkey; Forts/Castles
- Man with white beard and a white turban, kneeling next to a mosque window, reading the Quran. 23.8 x 18.2 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Gelatin Silver Prints; Carpets/Rugs; Hats; Praying; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites; Men; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair
- Sultan Ahmed Mosque, street seller in the snow. 18.1 x 23.9 cm, Circa 1930 (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Gelatin Silver Prints; Religious Sites; Men; Snow; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints
- Tombstones in Ahlat, Turkey. 23.8 x 16.1 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Tombs/Mausoleums; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mountains/Hills; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Religious Sites; Ahlat, Turkey
- Light fixtures, arches and windows in the interior of Suleymaniye Mosque. 23.8 x 18.2 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Religious Sites; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Carpets/Rugs; Architecture; Suleymaniye Mosque; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints
- Interior of dome in Suleymaniye Mosque. 23.9 x 18.1 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Suleymaniye Mosque; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Religious Sites
- Wall of windows and mihrab with men praying in the Blue Mosque in Istanbul, Turkey. 23.8 x 18.1 cm, Undated (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Religious Sites; Istanbul, Turkey; Carpets/Rugs; Praying; Men; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Gelatin Silver Prints; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits
- Boy in a sailor suit leaning on a studio prop boulder. 16.1 x 10.5 cm, Circa 1895 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Studio Photography; Books; Photographic Prints; Painted Backdrops; Hats; Bow Ties; Boys; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Haldun. "Souvenir to my dear aunt" 16.1 x 10.5 cm, 31 December 1902 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Istanbul, Turkey; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Constantinople; Children; Ottoman Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Books; Boys
- Boy with high white collar and a flower in his lapel. 16.5 x 10.7 cm, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Boys; Children; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Muhammed Sabri and Selahaddin. Two young men signed the photograph as a gift to their aunt. 23.9 x 17 cm, 1899 (Box 2, Folder Oversize)
  Men; Books; Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Painted Backdrops; Furnishings; Ottoman Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Woman in dark dress with pin on collar. 16.6 x 10.7 cm, 25 December; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  English Writing; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Jewelry; Women; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Woman in hat with a bow on her collar holding a baby in a gown. (French writing on the back, "The blessed child of the Arzuman family 1905"). 18.7 x 13.7 cm, Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Children; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Hats; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints
- Albanian Girl. 20.8 x 13.5 cm, 1890; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Women; Albumen Prints; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Turkish Writing; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Embroidery; Pottery; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man and a woman standing in a wedding dress. Kemaciyan. 21.7 x 13.2 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Weddings; Weddings; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Men; Women; Weddings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Facial Hair; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Gloves; Carpets/Rugs; Constantinople; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man with beard wearing a fez and a dark coat sitting in a chair. Same subject as ref106. 21.4 x 13.5 cm, 1880s; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Furnishings; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Albumen Prints; Men; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Man with beard in a white suit, dark coat and a fez, sitting on a chair. Same subject as ref105. 21.5 x 13.8 cm, 1888; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Furnishings; Books; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Men; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; French Writing; Ottoman Writing
- Soldiers with binoculars around their necks sitting on horses. 19.1 x 24.2 cm, 6 November 1918 (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Facial Hair; Facial Hair; Ottoman Writing; Odessa, Ukraine; Binoculars; Men; Flags; Group Portraits; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Horses; Military/Soldiers; Outdoors; Animals; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Uniforms
- A porter surrounded by street dogs. 25.9 x 18.6 cm, Circa 1880; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Animals; Facial Hair; Outdoors; Facial Hair; Doors/Entrances; Streets/Roads; French Writing; Hats; Food; Cigarettes; Dogs; Men; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Constantinople; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Two men in suits and two women wearing dresses and pearls with a small boy. 28.9 x 19.8 cm, 14 February 1930 (Box 2, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkish Writing; Furnishings; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Children; Boys; Women; Men; Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints
- Bosphorus strait with views of Maiden's Tower, Ayazma Mosque, and Rum Mehmed Pasha Mosque. A man in a rowboat is in the foreground. 23.2 x 31.2 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Bosphorus; Maiden's Tower; Buildings; Ports; Ayazma Mosque; Rum Mehmed Pasha Mosque; French Writing; Istanbul, Turkey; Mosques; Boats/Ships; Water; Architecture; Lighthouses; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites
- Golden Gate and Yedikule Fortress. Identical print to ref 134. 24.5 x 29.6 cm, 1898 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Golden Gate, Jerusalem; Buildings
- View of Cannon battery in a fort across the Bosphorus strait from Yoros Castle and Anadolu Kavagi, Istanbul. French writing on front: "Vue de la batterie de Madjian Kalé et d'Anatol Kavak." 23.2 x 31.5 cm, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Water; Men; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Cannons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Bosphorus; Forts/Castles; Anadolu Kavagi, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Weapons; Landscapes
- Grand Mosque of Bursa (Ulucami), Bursa. 19 x 25 cm, 1880; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Architecture; Bursa, Turkey; Mosques; Albumen Prints; Fountains; Religious Sites; Arabic Writing; Fountains; Carpets/Rugs; Boys; Men; Photographic Prints; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Grand Mosque of Bursa; Group Portraits
- Porte de Tripoli, Syrie. Port of Tripoli, modern day Lebanon. 20 x 26 cm, Undated; Bonfils, Felix (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Boats/Ships; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Ports; Syria; Lebanon; Mediterranean Sea; Water; Buildings; Landscapes
- Tomb in Eyup. Tomb of Abu Ayyub al-Ansari. Courtyard of Eyup Sultan Mosque, Istanbul, Turkey. 20 x 26 cm, 1870 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Religious Sites; Hats; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Streets/Roads; Eyup Sultan Mosque; Mosques; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; Outdoors; Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Architecture
- View of Heybeliada from Buyukada. 20 x 26 cm, 1890 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Outdoors; Sea of Marmara; Seas; Water; Prince Islands, Istanbul, Turkey; Buyukada, Istanbul, Turkey; Landscapes; Gelatin Silver Prints
- Mirahor Palace at Kagithane, Istanbul, Turkey. 20 x 26 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Boats/Ships; Rivers; Mirahor Palace; Constantinople; Kagithane, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Buildings; Outdoors; Umbrellas/Parasols; Palaces
- Ottoman troops at Wadi Halfa, Sudan. 20 x 26 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Weapons; Camels; Horses; Hats; Fez/Tarboush; Guns; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Sudan; Military/Soldiers; Men; Wadi Halfa, Sudan; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Animals; Group Portraits
- Friday procession to Yildiz Mosque, Yildiz Palace in the background to the left. 19 x 25 cm, 1880; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Constantinople; Mosques; Yildiz Hamidiye Mosque; Besiktas, Istanbul, Turkey; Guns; Religious Sites; Military/Soldiers; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Carriages/Coaches; Architecture; Weapons; Buildings; Palaces; Group Portraits; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints
- Nubian warriors, "soldiers of the Khedive," awaiting the arrival of the Sultan's "Khedive" (Governor of Egypt and Sudan) 77A. 20 x 26 cm, Undated; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Armor; Photographic Prints; Military/Soldiers; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Sudan; Flags; Weapons; Swords/Knives; Camels; Egypt; Men; Animals; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Turbans
- Buildings and gardens within the Fortress of Seven Towers, or the Yedikule Fortress. 20.7 x 26.7 cm, 1890 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Forts/Castles; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Istanbul, Turkey; Houses; Architecture; Gardens
- Buildings and mountains in Bursa. 20.7 x 26.8 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Houses; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mountains/Hills; Buildings; Bursa, Turkey; Landscapes
- Cattle in a river next to a road in Bursa, Turkey. 20.8 x26.9 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Cattle/Cows; Rivers; Animals; Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Children; Boys; Bridges; Outdoors; Streets/Roads
- Tomb of Sultan Murad II in the Muradiye Complex, Bursa, Turkey. 20.8 x 26.6 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Fountains; Children; Boys; Religious Sites; Bursa, Turkey; Tombs/Mausoleums; Constantinople; Individual Portraits
- Door of Yesil (Green) Mosque, or Mosque of Mehmed I, Bursa, Turkey. 26.7 x 20.8 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Doors/Entrances; Men; Mosques; Green Mosque, Bursa; Bursa, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Arabic Writing; Religious Sites; Individual Portraits
- Rooftops of Bursa with numerous mosques visible including the Grand Mosque of Bursa in the center-left of the image. 20.9 x 26.2 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Boys; Grand Mosque of Bursa; Bursa, Turkey; Children; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mountains/Hills; Mosques; Religious Sites; Landscapes
- Countryside in Bursa, facing north from behind Hudavendigar Mosque (in the foreground). 20.7 x 26.8 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  French Writing; Landscapes; Mosques; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Hudavendigar Mosque; Bursa, Turkey; Countryside/Rural; Architecture; Religious Sites
- Galata Tower, Istanbul. 26.6 x 20.6 cm, 1889 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)
  Streets/Roads; Buildings; Architecture; Istanbul, Turkey; Galata Tower; Constantinople; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Flags
- Three boys and a man standing in front of the door of Yesil (Green) Mosque, or Mosque of Mehmed I, Bursa, Turkey. 26.8 x 20.9 cm, 1894 (Box 3, Oversize unknown container)